Rahul Sekhar

93, 30th cross road Banashankari Stage 2 Bangalore - 560070, India ₱ +91 9916746045 ⊠ sekhar.rahul@gmail.com

I find great satisfaction in seeing problems tackled completely and elegantly. I involve myself wholeheartedly in everything I do and pride myself on my ability to pick up concepts and techniques quickly.

Skills

Languages In-depth knowledge of Javascript, Ruby, HTML and CSS. Experience with SQL, Python, PHP and shell scripting.

Frameworks In-depth experience with AngularJS, Rails and Wordpress. Experience with EmberJS, Backbone, Bootstrap, requireJS and AMD modules.

Methodology A strong focus on readable, modular, maintainable code. Experience with agile development. Much of the architecture I've designed has been based on the 12 factor pattern.

Web I make it a point to follow best practices and keep track of new developments and techniques. I have designed REST APIs, optimised webapps, worked with CDNs and mobile-friendly responsive layouts.

Tools Source control with git. Build processes with grunt and gulp. SASS, LESS and Compass as precompilers. Automated deployment with capistrano and githooks.

Testing BDD, TDD and thorough unit and integration testing using Jasmine, RSpec, Cucumber and Selenium. I believe tested code is a necessity not a luxury.

I have strong communication skills and am able to convey my ideas clearly and straightforwardly without jargon. I have lead a team and mentored developers, to produce quality code.

Work Experience

Personal

2015-current Member of Technical Staff, Nutanix, Bangalore.

I lead a team of front end developers at Nutanix, working on the interface for a number of technical tools, including sizing and quote generation for clusters, automated deployment and migration of workloads and healthcheck tools for clusters and migrated workloads. The company sets a great deal of importance on design and UX, and we ensure our interfaces are intuitive, clean, well designed and robust. My work here involves:

- Front end architectural decisions based on the requirements of each tool.
- Using modern tools and workflows to ensure code is well written and tested yet flexible and quick to write.
- Agile, scrum based methodology with two-week sprints for each project.
- Monitoring code quality across simultaneous projects.
- Interfacing with designers, stakeholders and technical experts to produce an intuitive, useful and well designed product.
- Refactoring and improving the workflow for legacy projects.

2012–2015 **Web Architect**, Kairi Studios, Bangalore.

At Kairi Studios I worked on webapps and sites for our clients from end to end – technical design, development and deployment. While I worked with the full stack here, due to the nature of our projects my focus was on front-end development. We received a great deal of appreciation for our interfaces, and the maintainability and robustness of our output.

Some of our projects included a redesign and extensive administration interface for NCF India, an internal academics and journaling system for small schools, and and an online store for childrens books. My work at Kairi involved:

- Architecture and tooling decisions based on client requirements.
- Behaviour driven development, with user focused stories and thorough automated testing.
- Projects that used AngularJS, Backbone, Ruby on Rails and Wordpress.
- Responsive, mobile-friendly layouts.
- Modern, creative and best practice based development.
- Documentation and maintenance of projects.

2011–2012 **Web Developer**, Freelance.

I put together websites in collaboration with some very talented designers as a freelance developer. My focus was to find creative solutions to problems and write clean, maintainable code that followed best practices. I made it a point to explore new technologies, frameworks, tools and techniques in an effort to stay up-to-date and remain flexible in my infrastructure choices, which has served me well.

Education

2007–2011 BMS College of Engineering, Bangalore.

B.E. in Telecommunication Engineering - First Class

1995–2007 **The Valley School**, *Bangalore*.

Indian School Certificate (ISC) - First class

Interests and extra-curricular activity

Music A passionate guitarist, I play in a small band and am in the process of writing and recording material for our first album. I have also been avidly involved in Tango dancing.

Hiking I enjoy treks and have completed a basic mountaineering course at the Himalayan Mountaineering Institute, Darjeeling with an A grade.

Sport A cyclist and runner, I've taken part in cycle tours and numerous runs.